ANGELO CORDON

FRONT-END ENGINEER

angelocordon@gmail.com www.angelocordon.com San Francisco, CA

ABOUT ME

For the past five years, I've been in leading positions building products that empower people to become their best selves. I enjoy merging technical complexities with visual aesthetics to create meaningful user experiences.

As a product designer and developer, I value the outcome of my work and strive to make an emotional impact to users. Through collaboration, I aim to gain actionable insights from stakeholders across an organization to make data-informed decisions. Previous entrepreneurial experiences has helped me appreciate company business goals and metrics.

SKILLS & ABILITIES

I'm as comfortable inside my terminal as I am with design tools. On a day to day basis, I use **Ruby / Rails, JavaScript, SCSS**, and other frontend technologies. I am also well versed with **Adobe Creative Suite, Sketch, InVision** and other prototyping tools.

OPEN CONTRIBUTIONS

Elsewhere, I enjoy spending time in open Slack communities where I mentor people when I can and learn from others as often as possible. I am a community administrator for CodeBuddies and participate in the Rands Leadership group along with CodeNewbie.

Currently, I am maintaining an open source project from the CodeBuddies community.

DungeonBuddies uses Docker, Ruby on Rails and ReactJS, deployed to Heroku servers.

PROFESSIONAL CAREER

Product Designer, Senior Software Engineer

Funderbolt (2017 - 2018)

Early in 2017, USEED restructured and rebranded as Funderbolt, a crowdfunding accelerator for student organizations.

- Led the design and front end development of content-dynamic campaign pages that helped inspire over \$1.6M in gifts from over 13,000 donors
- Delivered dashboard features using modern UX patterns to allow student fundraisers create their content easily
- Collaborated with different organization stakeholders to prototype new designs and features
- Developed a UI component library using mountain_view and VueJS to allow for engineers to build new user-facing pages and keep design consistent
- Conducted code and design reviews

Senior Software Engineer

USEED (2016 - 2017)

USEED, a crowdfunding platform for higher-ed institutions, served 110 colleges and universities including University of Washington, Arizona State University, and Princeton. Over the course of its history, USEED has launched over 690 campaigns.

- Refactored coupled and legacy code in a Rails 4 codebase through Test Driven Development and modern engineering patterns
- Built front end components with ReactJS

Lead Software Engineer

OppSites (2016)

- Delivered product features using Rails and Angular 1.x
- Implemented SMACSS pattern, reducing bloat in the code base
- Managed an international, outsourced engineering team to help deliver product features

Co-Founder, Principal Designer & Developer

A Vivid Visual (2013 - 2016)

- Developed prototypes with Ruby on Rails for early staged entrepreneurs
- Launch client online presence
- Clients included: Shiploop, Life Well Organized, SF Tikes Academy, The Great Baby Romp and many others

EDUCATIONAL HISTORY

BS in Media Arts & Animation

The Art Institute of California - San Francisco

• Graduated with Best Portfolio Award